Ra Mi-ran
라미란
Lee Do-hyun
이도현
Ahn Eun-jin
안은진
Yoo In-soo
유인수
Sam-sik's Mill
삼식의 방앗간
Choi Moo-sung - Jung Woong-in - Hong Bi-ra
최무성 - 정웅인 - 홍비라
Seo Yi-sook - Jang Won-young - Kang Mal-geum
서이숙 - 장원영 - 강말금
Kim Won-hae - Park Bo-kyung
김원해-박보경
Happy Farm
행복한 농장
The Good Bad Mother
좋은 나쁜 엄마
- Find anything? - Bring the cutter!
- 뭐라도 찾으셨나요? - 커터를 가져와!
- Hurry!
- 서두르다!
- Hurry up. - Yes, sir.
- 서둘러요. - 네, 선생님.
- Did you...? - Bring it up.
- 그랬어요...? - 올려봐.
Hey, come on.
이봐, 어서.
- Here. - Is it burned there?
- 여기. - 거기 불탔어요?
Push it.
밀어 넣으세요.
- Done? - Yes.
- 완료? - 예.
Kang-ho.
강호.
Wake...
일어나...
Wake up, Kang-ho.
일어나라 강호야.
Kang-ho...
강호...
No!
안돼!
No, Kang-ho!
안돼, 강호!
- Ma'am, calm down. - Kang-ho!
- 부인, 진정하세요. - 강호!
Kang-ho!
강호!
Please save him!
그를 구해주세요!
My son!
내 아들!
My baby!
내 아기!
My baby! Please save him!
내 아기! 그를 구해주세요!
Please!
제발!
First of all,
우선,
we successfully stopped the hemorrhaging.
우리는 출혈을 성공적으로 멈추었습니다.
But his brain and body remain swollen.
그러나 그의 뇌와 몸은 여전히 ​​부어있습니다.
His cervical spine was fractured,
경추뼈가 골절됐고,
and he suffered an injury to his spinal cord.
그리고 그는 척수 부상을 입었습니다.
Even if he gains consciousness,
의식을 얻더라도
I'm afraid he won't be able to return to his normal life for some time.
그 사람이 돌아오지 못할까 봐 걱정이에요 한동안 정상적인 생활을 하게 됩니다.
Food?
음식?
You're inviting me to eat,
나를 식사에 초대하고 계시네요.
when I've never been able to enjoy a meal with you?
내가 한 번도 그럴 수 없었을 때 너랑 같이 식사할래?
You're dozing off because you're full and it's warm.
너 때문에 졸고 있는 거야 배도 부르고 따뜻해요.
Study.
공부하다.
You got it wrong again.
또 틀렸어요.
Learning Chinese characters is mandatory for the bar exam.
한자 학습 변호사 시험에 필수입니다.
Rewrite the ones you got wrong a hundred times and memorize them again.
틀린 부분을 다시 작성하세요. 수백번을 반복하고 다시 외워보세요.
Run!
달리다!
Darn it.
젠장.
What is he...?
그 사람은 뭐죠...?
Mom...
엄마...
You'll doze off on a full stomach.
배가 가득 차서 졸게 될 것입니다.
I told you a million times.
나는 당신에게 백만 번 말했습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Dowon Hospital
도원병원
You should eat.
먹어야 해.
How could she have an appetite when her child is dying?
그녀는 어떻게 식욕을 가질 수 있었습니까? 그 아이가 죽을 때?
Dying?
사망?
Who's dying?
누가 죽어가고 있나요?
He's still breathing.
그는 아직 숨을 쉬고 있습니다.
Both his pulse and blood pressure are stable.
맥박과 혈압 모두 안정적이다.
His hands and feet are warm.
그의 손과 발은 따뜻하다.
His body is still functioning.
그의 몸은 여전히 ​​​​기능하고 있습니다.
My son won't die.
내 아들은 죽지 않을 거예요.
No.
아니요.
I won't...
나는하지 않을 것이다 ...
I won't let him die.
나는 그가 죽도록 놔두지 않을 것이다.
The Good Bad Mother
좋은 나쁜 엄마
Short! A double play!
짧다! 더블 플레이!
Good play!
좋은 플레이!
Yes!
예!
Good throw. Nice play!
잘 던졌어요. 좋은 플레이!
- Well done. - It's all thanks to you.
- 잘했어요. - 다 당신 덕분이에요.
This is how our team made it to the Korean Series...
우리 팀은 이렇게 만들었어요 한국시리즈까지...
after only two years in the league.
리그에서 단 2년 만에.
You were terrific today! Applause!
오늘 정말 멋졌어요! 박수 갈채!
You were incredible!
정말 대단했어요!
Goodness. Yes?
맙소사. 예?
Prosecutor Choi was in an accident.
최 검사가 사고를 당했습니다.
He's in the ICU at Dowon Hospital.
도원병원 중환자실에 있어요.
What?
무엇?
What a mess.
정말 엉망이군요.
He could've just forged the document.
그 사람은 문서를 위조했을 수도 있어요.
Yet he went all the way there just to get that seal?
그래도 그 사람은 끝까지 갔어 그냥 인장을 받으러 거기 있는 거야?
What about the other driver?
다른 운전자는 어떻습니까?
They haven't been identified yet.
아직 신원이 확인되지 않았습니다.
The roads are blanketed with CCTV cameras these days,
도로는 덮혀있다 요즘 CCTV 카메라는
yet they can't find the guy?
그런데 그 사람을 못 찾나요?
The truck was a burner vehicle.
트럭은 버너 차량이었습니다.
Also, it was found after it'd been set on fire,
게다가 불이 붙은 후에 발견됐는데,
and no fingerprints were recovered.
지문은 복구되지 않았습니다.
What?
무엇?
A burner vehicle?
버너 차량?
It was a burner vehicle?
버너 차량이었나?
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
Right. Hold on.
오른쪽. 기다리다.
What happened to Oh Tae-soo's daughter?
오태수 딸에게 무슨 일이?
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
He most likely won't make it.
그는 아마도 성공하지 못할 것입니다.
Well done.
잘하셨어요.
Kang-ho.
강호.
Hold on.
기다리다.
That means...
즉...
he's still alive.
그는 아직 살아있습니다.
What do we do?
우리는 무엇을 합니까?
What if...
만약에...
they find out?
그들이 알아냈어?
Chairman Song
송회장
I'll take care of that, so don't worry.
그건 내가 처리할 테니 걱정하지 마세요.
Just rest up for a few days.
며칠만 쉬어보세요.
Hello, Chairman Song.
안녕하세요, 송회장님.
Goodness. Thank God.
선량. 하느님 감사합니다.
I heard your daughter wasn't in the car when it happened.
당신 딸은 그렇지 않다고 들었는데 그 일이 일어났을 때 차 안에서.
What a relief.
정말 다행이네요.
My heart is still heavy when I think of Prosecutor Choi.
그럴 때면 아직도 마음이 무겁다. 최 검사가 생각난다.
Tell me about it.
그것에 대해 말해 보세요.
I just saw him, and it broke my heart.
방금 그를 봤는데 마음이 아팠어요.
Anyway, both you and your daughter must be shocked.
아무튼 너도 그렇고 너도 그렇고 딸은 충격을 받았을 것입니다.
Take care of yourselves.
몸 조심하세요.
Let's catch up in person soon.
곧 직접 만나보도록 하겠습니다.
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
He has a heavy heart?
그 사람 마음이 무겁나요?
Find that hit-and-run driver this instant.
지금 당장 그 뺑소니 운전자를 찾아보세요.
Darn it! Everything's ruined!
젠장! 모든 것이 망가졌습니다!
Of course.
물론.
Everything else is fine.
다른 모든 것은 괜찮습니다.
But he hurt his leg,
그런데 그 분이 다리를 다치셨어요.
so it'll take some time for him to recover.
그래서 그 사람이 회복되려면 시간이 좀 걸릴 거예요.
I asked them to find an experienced farmhand.
나는 그들에게 경험 있는 농장 일꾼을 찾아달라고 부탁했습니다.
But it's hard to hire anyone since it's farming season.
하지만 누군가를 고용하는 것은 어렵습니다 농사철이니까.
Thank you in advance, Mr. Son.
미리 감사드립니다, 손 선생님.
Don't worry about the pigs,
돼지는 걱정하지 마세요.
and just focus on Kang-ho.
강호에게만 집중하세요.
Yes. All right, bye.
예. 알았어, 안녕.
What did she say?
그녀가 뭐라고 말했습니까?
How is Kang-ho?
강호는 어때요?
He must've broken his leg.
그 사람 다리가 부러진 게 틀림없어요.
- Oh, dear. - Goodness.
- 아, 얘야. - 맙소사.
He broke his mom's heart when he left.
그는 떠났을 때 엄마의 마음을 아프게 했습니다.
He's being punished for it.
그는 그 때문에 처벌을 받고 있습니다.
Gosh, don't say something like that about our neighbor.
맙소사, 아무 말도 하지 마세요 우리 이웃에 대해서도 마찬가지입니다.
That's exactly why I'm saying this.
이것이 바로 제가 이 말을 하는 이유입니다.
She's a fool.
그녀는 바보입니다.
She was always fixated on his studies.
그녀는 항상 그의 연구에 집착했습니다.
All her hard work only made him into such an impudent son.
그녀의 모든 노력은 단지 그를 이렇게 뻔뻔스러운 아들로 만들었습니다.
As a parent,
부모로서,
you shouldn't bad-mouth another parent's child.
다른 부모의 아이를 욕해서는 안 됩니다.
Honestly, Sam-sik is the most impudent one of all.
솔직히 삼식은 가장 뻔뻔한 사람.
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Why are you bringing him up right now?
왜 지금 그 사람을 키우는 거죠?
I mean, it's not like he did anything serious.
내 말은, 그가 심각한 짓을 한 것은 아닌 것 같다는 거죠.
Are you serious right now?
지금 진심인가요?
Let's be frank.
솔직하게 말해보자.
Raise your hand if you've never been robbed by him.
있다면 손을 들어보세요 그 사람에게 강탈당한 적이 없습니다.
From watermelons and red peppers to rice wine...
수박과 고추부터 막걸리까지…
I still don't get why he stole that talisman from Mr. Son's gate.
아직도 그 사람이 왜 훔쳤는지 이해가 안 돼요 손 씨 집의 그 부적.
- Gosh. - Even a talisman?
- 이런. - 부적이라도요?
Have you gone insane?
미쳤어?
I'm going to kill you with my own hands today!
오늘은 내 손으로 널 죽이겠다!
- Stop it. - Goodness!
- 그만해요. - 맙소사!
- Gosh! - What are you doing?
- 이런! - 뭐하세요?
Gosh, that's enough!
맙소사, 그거면 충분해요!
- That's enough! - Hello.
- 충분해요! - 안녕하세요.
Why did you bring that dog when we're eating?
우리 밥 먹을 때 왜 그 개를 데려왔나요?
- Goodness. - Gosh.
- 맙소사. - 이런.
Is the food ready?
음식은 준비됐나요?
You're having the awful spicy noodles.
당신은 정말 매운 국수를 먹고 있습니다.
- What? - What did you just say?
- 무엇? - 방금 뭐라고 했어요?
The food is what?
음식은 무엇입니까?
Awful.
끔찍한.
What? You said the same thing.
무엇? 당신도 같은 말을 했어요.
You said Sung-ae couldn't cook to save her life.
성애가 생명을 구하기 위해 요리를 못한다고 하더군요.
Don't eat it.
먹지 마세요.
- Don't eat it. - What?
- 먹지 마세요. - 무엇?
Don't eat it!
먹지 마세요!
- Come on. - Sung-ae.
- 어서 해봐요. - 성애.
- Bring it back!
- 다시 가져와!
Why are they always fighting?
그들은 왜 항상 싸우나요?
They're setting an awful example for us.
그들은 우리에게 끔찍한 본보기를 보이고 있습니다.
At least we'll learn how to fight well.
적어도 우리는 잘 싸우는 방법을 배울 것입니다.
Goodness me.
맙소사.
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
We're fully booked for the next two days.
앞으로 이틀간 예약이 꽉 찼습니다.
One minute.
1분.
There's an opening this Friday at 8 p.m.
이번주 금요일 저녁 8시에 오픈이 있습니다.
Okay. I'll reserve it for you.
좋아요. 당신을 위해 예약해 두겠습니다.
Thank you. Goodbye.
감사합니다. 안녕히 가세요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
You're raking in all the money in this neighborhood.
당신은 모든 것을 긁어 모으고 있습니다. 이 동네 돈이요.
I wish Bo-bae would quit her studies...
보배가 공부 그만뒀으면 좋겠다...
and learn some useful skills like this.
이와 같은 유용한 기술을 배우십시오.
She's always hanging out...
그녀는 항상 어울리고 있어요...
with her friends at night, saying she's studying.
밤에는 친구들과 함께, 공부 중이라고 하더군요.
She needs to be more careful.
그녀는 좀 더 조심해야 합니다.
A rape and murder case occurred in the next neighborhood.
성폭행, 살인 사건이 발생했다 다음 동네에서.
Right. I heard.
오른쪽. 들었어.
He followed her knowing she lives alone,
그는 그녀가 혼자 사는 것을 알고 그녀를 따라갔고,
and attacked her as soon as she opened the door.
그리고 그녀가 문을 열자마자 그녀를 공격했습니다.
Really? So did they catch him?
정말? 그래서 그를 잡았나요?
No. That's why everyone is panicking.
아니요. 그래서 모두가 당황하고 있습니다.
You guys live alone too, right?
너희들도 혼자 살고 있지?
You should be careful.
조심해야합니다.
They ought to catch and grind him up.
그들은 그를 잡아서 갈아버려야 합니다.
That's pretty.
예쁘네요.
It's a miracle he can breathe on his own.
그가 스스로 숨을 쉴 수 있다는 것은 기적입니다.
Let's move him to a general ward and monitor him.
그를 장군으로 옮기자 그를 보호하고 모니터링하세요.
In the general ward, you're responsible for taking care of his waste.
일반병동에서는 자신의 쓰레기를 처리할 책임이 있습니다.
The drainage bag is connected here.
배수백은 여기에 연결됩니다.
This is the suppository.
이것은 좌약입니다.
He could get an infection without proper care,
적절한 치료를 받지 않으면 감염될 수 있습니다.
so please pay close attention.
그러니 세심한 주의를 기울여 주시기 바랍니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
The number you have called does not exist. Please check...
당신이 전화한 전화번호 존재하지 않습니다. 확인해주세요...
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
Can I confirm her number again?
그 사람 번호를 다시 확인해도 될까요?
You've already done so three times, ma'am.
벌써 세 번이나 그러셨어요, 부인.
Then why does it say that the number doesn't exist?
그럼 왜 그런 말이 나오지? 그 번호는 존재하지 않나요?
Maybe it doesn't.
어쩌면 그렇지 않을 수도 있습니다.
Or maybe she changed her number.
아니면 전화번호를 바꿨을 수도 있어요.
Then could you give me her home number or address?
그럼 나한테 줄래? 집 전화번호나 주소는요?
Ma'am, we aren't allowed to disclose such information to strangers.
부인, 공개하면 안 돼요 낯선 사람에게 그러한 정보를 제공합니다.
I'm not a stranger.
나는 낯선 사람이 아닙니다.
She's my son's fiancée and my daughter-in-law.
그녀는 내 아들의 약혼자이자 며느리입니다.
Ma'am.
부인.
Mothers don't usually ask a hospital's administration office...
엄마들은 보통 아무것도 묻지 않아요 병원 행정실..
for their daughter-in-law's number.
며느리 번호 때문에요.
- Mom!
- 엄마!
Really?
정말?
Ms. Jo taught you English?
조 선생님이 영어를 가르쳐 주셨나요?
What did you learn?
무엇을 배웠나요?
Why did that woman teach them such terrifying words?
그 여자는 왜 가르쳤나요? 그게 그렇게 무서운 말인가요?
Guys, don't meet her anymore.
얘들아 이제 그 사람 만나지마
No.
아니요.
We need to learn English if we want to see you soon.
우리는 영어를 배워야 해요 빨리 만나고 싶다면.
I love the U.S.
나는 미국을 사랑합니다
All right.
알았어.
I hope you learn English quickly so we can live together.
영어를 배우셨으면 좋겠습니다 빨리 같이 살 수 있도록.
By the way, who's that guy behind you?
그런데 뒤에 있는 저 사람은 누구죠?
What?
무엇?
Stop pranking me and go to bed, okay?
장난 그만 치고 자러 가, 알았지?
I'll talk to you tomorrow.
내일 얘기 좀 할게요.
A rape and murder case occurred...
강간살인 사건이 발생했습니다...
in the next neighborhood.
다음 동네에서.
Mi-joo.
미주.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Mi-joo!
미주!
Bang Sam-sik?
방삼식?
Darn it.
젠장.
You have all those normal clothes, and you gave me this?
당신은 그 모든 정상을 가지고 있습니다 옷인데 이걸 나한테 줬어?
What? Do I?
무엇? 나도요?
You should've just gone home after you wer released.
넌 그냥 갔어야 했는데 석방된 후 집으로.
Why did you come here?
왜 여기에 왔나요?
Goodness.
선량.
I'm seriously regretting it myself.
나 자신도 진심으로 후회하고 있다.
Right. I'm supposed to give you tofu since you've been released.
오른쪽. 내가 너한테 줘야지 당신이 석방된 이후로 두부.
- You already gave me something. - What?
- 당신은 이미 나에게 뭔가를 줬어요. - 무엇?
A good beating.
좋은 구타.
A painful one.
고통스러운 것.
By the way, how did you know I lived here?
그런데, 내가 여기 사는 걸 어떻게 알았나요?
Well...
음...
A long time ago,
오래 전,
you said it was your dream...
네 꿈이라고 했잖아...
to open up your own nail salon.
자신의 네일 살롱을 열려면
Right.
오른쪽.
You said the name would be Nail & Nail,
이름이 네일앤네일이라고 하셨는데,
and how brilliant the idea was.
그 아이디어가 얼마나 훌륭했는지요.
So I looked up the name just in case.
그래서 혹시나 하는 마음에 이름을 찾아봤습니다.
And guess what? I found it.
그리고 무엇을 추측합니까? 나는 그것을 찾았다.
You're incredible. You remembered that?
당신은 대단해요. 그거 기억나?
Of course I did.
물론 그랬습니다.
I remember watching you being born while I was being carried...
당신이 존재하는 걸 지켜본 기억이 나네요 안고 있는 동안 태어났어...
on my mom's back.
엄마 등에.
I'm the first guy who saw you naked.
나는 당신의 알몸을 본 첫 번째 남자입니다.
- You lunatic. - Goodness.
- 미친놈아. - 맙소사.
You were pretty.
당신은 예뻤습니다.
Gosh.
이런.
I never visited you while you were incarcerated.
당신이 투옥되어 있는 동안 나는 당신을 방문한 적이 없습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Why would you visit me...
왜 나를 방문하겠습니까?
when I was incarcerated for committing a crime?
내가 범죄를 저질러 투옥되었을 때?
You didn't commit a crime.
당신은 범죄를 저지르지 않았습니다.
You were used by those bad guys.
당신은 그 나쁜 놈들에게 이용당했어요.
You were merely a victim.
당신은 단지 피해자일 뿐이었습니다.
Mi-joo.
미주.
Yes?
예?
I realized being like that...
그런 존재라는 걸 깨달았어...
was the worst sin you could commit.
당신이 지을 수 있는 가장 큰 죄였습니다.
What?
무엇?
Letting others use you.
다른 사람들이 당신을 사용하도록 허용합니다.
And...
그리고...
not being able to do anything about it because you have no power,
아무것도 할 수 없다는 것 너한테 힘이 없으니까 그러는 거야.
money, or connections.
돈이든, 인맥이든.
Just take it.
그냥 가져가세요.
It's free.
그것은 무료입니다.
From what I heard,
내가 들은 바로는,
working on fishing vessels is hard work.
어선에서 일하는 것은 힘든 일입니다.
Take care of yourself.
몸 조심하세요.
And don't get caught stealing things again.
그리고 다시는 물건을 훔치다가 잡히지 마세요.
If I ever steal anything again,
내가 또 뭔가를 훔치면,
it's going to be your heart.
그것은 당신의 마음이 될 것입니다.
- Bye. - Do you still like Kang-ho?
- 안녕. - 아직도 강호를 좋아하시나요?
- What are you talking about? Go. - Do you?
- 무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요? 가다. - 당신은?
What's with you? Go!
당신은 무엇입니까? 가다!
Just go. Go home safely.
그냥 가세요. 집에 안전하게 가세요.
Let's be honest, I'm way more handsome than him.
솔직히 말해서 내가 그 사람보다 훨씬 더 잘생겼어요.
Yes, you're right.
네, 당신 말이 맞아요.
You're more handsome.
당신이 더 잘 생겼어요.
Thanks for today and this gift. Go now.
오늘과 이 선물에 감사드립니다. 지금 가세요.
- You're handsome. - But...
- 당신은 잘 생겼어요. - 하지만...
Bye.
안녕.
Release
출시
Goodness.
맙소사.
Goodness. Look at the size of this gem.
선량. 이 보석의 크기를 보세요.
This is bigger than Mr. Son's tomatoes.
손 씨의 토마토보다 더 크다.
You're supposed to buy your parents longjohns with your first paycheck.
부모님한테 사드려야지 첫 월급을 받은 롱존스.
But you can't flaunt that,
하지만 그걸 자랑할 수는 없어요.
and you like to show off.
그리고 당신은 자랑하는 것을 좋아합니다.
I also felt bad...
나도 기분이 나빴어..
that you lost your wedding ring ages ago.
당신이 오래 전에 결혼반지를 잃어버렸다고요.
I never lost it.
나는 그것을 잃어버린 적이 없습니다.
I hid it in the doenjang crock...
된장 도기 속에 숨겨놨는데...
so you wouldn't steal it.
그러면 당신은 그것을 훔치지 않을 것입니다.
But you still found it and sold it.
그러나 당신은 여전히 ​​​​그것을 찾아서 팔았습니다.
I felt so happy back then.
그때는 너무 행복했어요.
- What? - Because...
- 무엇? - 왜냐면...
I truly despised the ring your dad had gotten for me.
나는 정말로 반지를 경멸했다 네 아버지가 날 위해 사셨어.
The gem was so tiny, it was barely visible.
보석은 너무 작아서 거의 보이지 않았습니다.
What?
무엇?
You'd gained a lot of weight back then,
그땐 살이 많이 쪘었지.
so the fat was covering the gem.
그래서 지방이 보석을 덮고 있었던 것입니다.
Thank you so much, Sam-sik.
정말 고마워요, 삼식 씨.
Goodness, Sam-sik.
맙소사, 삼식.
- My baby. - What are you doing?
- 내 아기. - 뭐하세요?
- Come here. - What...?
- 이리 오세요. - 무엇...?
Goodness, my baby.
맙소사, 자기야.
I can't believe you got me a ring.
당신이 나에게 반지를 주다니 믿을 수가 없어요.
- Gosh, you precious thing. - Goodness!
- 이런, 소중한 것. - 맙소사!
It's nothing.
그것은 아무것도 아니다.
Just live a long life.
그냥 오래오래 사세요.
I'll make tons of money so you can live comfortably.
난 돈을 엄청나게 벌 테니까 편안하게 생활하실 수 있습니다.
- Gosh, my baby. - Anyone home?
- 이런, 자기야. - 집에 누구 없나요?
Let me go!
날 보내줘!
I didn't steal it! I got it as my paycheck!
나는 그것을 훔치지 않았다! 월급으로 받았어요!
All right. Let's talk at the station.
괜찮은. 역에서 얘기하자.
Can you please just hear him out?
그의 말을 좀 들어주실 수 있나요?
He said they gave it to him!
줬다고 하더라구요!
Was he going to steal things...
물건을 훔치려는 걸까...
to make our lives comfortable?
우리의 삶을 편안하게 만들기 위해?
Was that it?
그거였어?
Bye.
안녕.
- Bye. - Dad.
- 안녕. - 아빠.
- Hey. - Gosh.
- 여기요. - 이런.
Goodness.
선량.
Excuse me!
실례합니다!
Our son hasn't come out yet.
우리 아들은 아직 나오지 않았어요.
- What's his name? - Bang Sam-sik.
- 그 사람 이름이 뭐예요? - 방삼식.
He's...
그는 ...
not on the list.
목록에 없습니다.
- What? - That can't be.
- 무엇? - 그럴 리가 없어.
He said he needed money for a release deposit,
석방 보증금을 위한 돈이 필요하다고 하더군요.
so I transferred it to him yesterday.
그래서 어제 그 사람에게 전달했어요.
A release deposit?
해제 보증금?
You know,
아시다시피,
it's to guarantee he'll behave once he's out.
그가 나가면 그가 행동할 것이라는 것을 보장하기 위한 것입니다.
There's no such thing.
그런 건 없습니다.
Release deposits don't exist!
릴리스 보증금이 존재하지 않습니다!
My goodness!
이럴 수가!
Do you know a Bang Sam-sik?
방삼식이라는 사람을 아시나요?
Of course I do.
물론이죠.
- He was released a week ago. - What?
- 일주일 전에 석방됐어요. - 무엇?
- A week ago? - Yes.
- 일주일 전요? - 예.
I was totally speechless.
나는 완전히 말문이 막혔다.
He stole the penitentiary's towels, soap, and toothpaste.
그는 교도소 물건을 훔쳤습니다. 수건, 비누, 치약.
Let's go.
갑시다.
- Darn it! - Wait.
- 젠장! - 기다리다.
How much did you send him?
그 사람한테 얼마를 보냈어요?
$5000...
$5000...
You son of a gun!
총잡이야!
Then is it Ms. Jung's fault for laying out the pesticide bottles by the road?
그렇다면 누워있는 것은 정씨의 잘못인가? 길가에 살충제 병을 내놓았나요?
Or is it Mr. Son's fault for running over them on his bike?
아니면 손씨의 잘못인가? 자전거를 타고 그 사람들을 치나요?
My son is a prosecutor at Seoul Central District Prosecutors' Office.
내 아들은 서울 검사입니다 중앙지방검찰청.
He got the top score on the bar exam.
그는 변호사 시험에서 최고 점수를 받았습니다.
Goodness.
선량.
Look. My eyes aren't even.
바라보다. 내 눈은 고르지 않습니다.
Can I retrieve the land even if it's under my brother's name?
그래도 땅을 되찾을 수 있을까? 내 동생 이름으로 되어 있어?
- This is about your land? - Correct.
- 이것은 당신의 땅에 관한 것입니까? - 옳은.
She'd taken out a dozen insurances.
그녀는 12개의 보험에 가입했습니다.
- He turned out to be married. - Oh, dear.
-그는 결혼한 것으로 밝혀졌습니다. - 아, 얘야.
Please put in a good word for me once he wakes up.
좋은말씀해주세요 나를 위해 그가 깨어 나면.
- Please. - Okay.
- 제발. - 좋아요.
- Thanks. - Goodness.
- 감사해요. - 맙소사.
No, I'm sorry.
아니요, 죄송합니다.
- That's it for today. - But...
- 오늘은 여기까지입니다. - 하지만...
Come again tomorrow.
내일 다시 오세요.
What about just me?
나만 어때요?
Gosh.
이런.
She's done for the day.
그녀는 오늘의 일을 마쳤습니다.
Kang-ho.
강호.
Look at this.
이것 좀 보세요.
They're all waiting for you to wake up.
그들은 모두 당신이 깨어나기를 기다리고 있습니다.
So...
그래서...
wake up soon, okay?
빨리 일어나, 응?
Your fingernails have grown so much.
손톱이 많이 자랐네요.
Nurse.
간호사.
Nurse!
간호사!
Kang-ho woke up!
강호 일어났어!
My son woke up!
내 아들이 일어났어요!
Kang-ho!
강호!
Kang-ho. It's me, Mom.
강호. 나예요, 엄마.
Do you recognize me?
당신은 나를 알아보나요?
Kang-ho! It's me.
강호! 나야.
Your mom.
당신의 엄마.
What's wrong?
무슨 일이야?
It's me, Kang-ho.
나야, 강호.
As of now we've given him all the immediate treatments.
지금 우리는 그에게 모든 즉각적인 치료.
The rehabilitation department...
재활학과..
will take over...
인수할 것이다...
and monitor him.
그리고 그를 모니터링하세요.
Doctor.
의사.
He'll be able to walk again, right?
그 사람은 다시 걸을 수 있겠죠?
As long as we keep up with the treatment.
우리가 치료를 계속하는 한.
Right?
오른쪽?
Let's hope for the best as he receives his treatment.
최선을 다하길 바라자 그는 치료를 받습니다.
I've seen many patients walk again after rehabilitation.
나는 많은 환자들을 보아왔다. 재활 후 다시 걸어보세요.
- I see. - However,
- 알겠어요. - 그러나,
you need to understand he'll be very different...
당신은 이해해야 그 사람은 많이 다를 거예요...
from the person he used to be.
그 사람이었던 사람에게서.
When you injure your head,
머리를 다쳤을 때,
you sometimes lose most of the memories prior to the accident.
당신은 때때로 대부분의 것을 잃습니다 사고 전 기억.
And as for your son, he only has memories...
그리고 당신의 아들은 추억밖에 없어요...
of his childhood.
그의 어린 시절.
So it's like he's become a child once again.
그래서 다시 어린아이가 된 것 같아요.
He also lacks cognitive ability right now.
그 사람도 지금 인지능력이 부족해요.
We call that retrograde amnesia.
우리는 이를 역행성 기억상실증이라고 부릅니다.
He's like...
그는 마치...
a seven-year-old right now.
지금은 일곱 살이에요.
A seven-year-old?
일곱 살짜리?
Simply put, he's...
쉽게 말하면 그 사람은...
- ...stupid? - ...stupid.
- ...바보야? - ...멍청한.
Well, maybe not to that extent, but...
뭐, 그 정도까지는 아닐지도 모르지만...
Anyway, let's keep an eye on him.
어쨌든, 그를 계속 지켜보자.
Okay.
좋아요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
- You should go now. - Yes, ma'am.
- 지금 가셔야 해요. - 네, 부인.
And could you keep the siren off?
그리고 사이렌을 꺼주실 수 있나요?
Okay.
좋아요.
Ms. Jin?
진씨?
Yes.
예.
Hey, you're back.
안녕, 돌아왔구나
You're back.
당신은 돌아왔다.
- I'm sorry for the trouble. - Not at all.
- 불편을 끼쳐드려 죄송합니다. - 별말씀을요.
Pour our guest a drink first.
손님에게 먼저 술을 부어주세요.
I refuse to drink alcohol.
나는 술을 거부합니다.
Goodness.
선량.
He flew in from Canada six months ago.
그는 6개월 전에 캐나다에서 비행기를 타고 왔습니다.
He understands Korean but can't speak it.
그는 한국어를 이해하지만 말을 할 수 없습니다.
You're majoring in Korean at Chungjin University, right?
한국어를 전공하시네요 청진대학교 맞죠?
You're correct.
당신 말이 맞아요.
- Right. - You said...
- 오른쪽. - 당신이 말했잖아요...
you needed help with your farm.
농장에 도움이 필요했어요.
His father runs a pig farm back in Canada.
그의 아버지는 캐나다에서 돼지 농장을 운영하고 있습니다.
He wanted to learn about Korean pig farms...
그는 한국의 돼지 농장에 대해 배우고 싶었습니다.
and the language itself, so he's working part-time here.
그리고 언어 그 자체, 그래서 그는 여기서 파트타임으로 일하고 있어요.
Your name is Andrea, right?
당신 이름은 안드레아 맞죠?
Yes.
예.
That's his name.
그게 그 사람 이름이에요.
I don't know what your name means,
나는 당신의 이름이 무엇을 의미하는지 모릅니다.
but if I had to guess, I'd say it means something like "impolite."
하지만 추측해야 한다면 이렇게 말하겠습니다. 그것은 "무례한"과 같은 것을 의미합니다.
Because you're not pouring me a drink!
왜냐면 당신은 나에게 술을 따르지 않거든요!
- Pour him some. - Pour me some.
- 그에게 좀 부어주세요. - 좀 부어주세요.
It must be so tough for you all.
여러분 모두에게 너무 힘든 일이겠죠.
Don't regard it as a hardship.
그것을 고난으로 여기지 마십시오.
What kind of jerk is teaching you such difficult words?
무슨 멍청이가 가르치는거야? 그렇게 어려운 말을 해?
This jerk.
이 바보.
Korean: Don't Regard It as a Hardship
한국어: 어려움으로 여기지 마세요
Gosh.
이런.
By the way,
그건 그렇고,
has Kang-ho been discharged from the hospital?
강호는 퇴원했나요?
Yes.
예.
Goodness.
선량.
It must've bothered him to have treated you so harshly.
그게 그 사람을 귀찮게 했을 게 틀림없어 당신을 너무 가혹하게 대했습니다.
That's why he drove recklessly and got into an accident.
그래서 그 사람은 난폭하게 운전을 했어 그리고 사고를 당했습니다.
I can't tell you when it'll be,
언제가 될지는 말씀드릴 수 없습니다.
but when they set their date again, make sure you're there at the wedding.
하지만 그들이 다시 날짜를 정했을 때, 결혼식에 꼭 참석하세요.
You must do that as his mom.
당신은 그의 엄마로서 그렇게 해야 합니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Why did she plant so many?
그녀는 왜 그렇게 많이 심었을까?
This saves her money from buying pig feed.
이를 통해 그녀는 돼지 사료를 구입하는 데 드는 돈을 절약할 수 있습니다.
She's always been hard-working.
그녀는 항상 열심히 일했습니다.
What good is that when she has an impudent son?
그녀에게 뻔뻔스러운 아들이 있으면 무슨 소용이 있겠습니까?
Gosh. There you go again.
이런. 또 가네요.
But then again, I'm in no position to bad-mouth her son.
하지만 다시 말하지만 난 그렇지 않아 아들을 욕하는 입장.
- When is Sam-sik being released? - When is Mi-joo coming?
- 삼식은 언제 출시되나요? - 미주는 언제 오나요?
Let's get back to work.
다시 일하러 갑시다.
Let's do that.
그렇게 해보자.
- I'm sorry. - What?
- 죄송합니다. - 무엇?
- Goodness. - Don't be.
- 맙소사. - 그러지 마세요.
- It's been a while. - This is killing me.
- 오랜만이에요. - 정말 죽겠다.
- Goodness. - Thank you.
- 맙소사. - 감사합니다.
Gosh, I guess it was strenuous.
맙소사, 힘들었던 것 같아요.
I'm sore all over.
온몸이 아프다
Of course.
물론.
- Gosh, I'm exhausted. - Gum-ja, here.
- 맙소사, 나 지쳤어. - 검자, 여기요.
Goodness. What are you doing?
선량. 뭐하세요?
I don't need that.
나는 그런 것이 필요하지 않습니다.
I'm doing this for my sake.
나는 나를 위해 이 일을 하고 있다.
You must be insane.
당신은 미친 게 분명합니다.
You're making us feel bad.
당신은 우리를 기분 나쁘게 만들고 있어요.
Gosh, you're making me feel bad.
이런, 당신 때문에 기분이 나빠지네요.
We didn't even visit Kang-ho at the hospital.
우리는 강호를 병원에 방문하지도 않았습니다.
Right. Where is he?
오른쪽. 그는 어디에 있나요?
Is he here with you?
그 사람이 당신과 함께 여기 있나요?
Well...
음...
No.
아니요.
Why would he be here?
그 사람이 왜 여기 있겠어요?
He's probably back at his own home.
그 사람은 아마 자기 집으로 돌아왔을 거예요.
He's a successful prosecutor.
그는 성공한 검사입니다.
He must have work piled up after months of being at the hospital.
그 사람은 나중에 일이 쌓여 있었나 봐요 병원에 입원한 지 몇 달.
Thank goodness.
맙소사.
I was worried sick.
나는 걱정했다.
Is he all better now?
이제 그 사람은 다 나아졌나요?
Yes.
예.
Kang-ho, aren't you hungry?
강호야, 배고프지 않니?
Let's eat.
먹자.
Do you remember this?
이것을 기억하시나요?
This was your first birthday.
이번이 너의 첫 번째 생일이었어.
You're holding a gavel.
당신은 의사봉을 들고 있습니다.
You were destined to become a prosecutor.
당신은 검사가 될 운명이었습니다.
Don't you agree?
동의하지 않나요?
And this was your elementary-school graduation.
그리고 이게 너의 초등학교 졸업식이었지.
We had our first heavy snow in 30 years, so the graduation took place in the gym.
30년 만에 처음으로 큰 눈이 내렸습니다. 그래서 졸업식이 체육관에서 열렸어요.
And this was your middle-school graduation.
그리고 이게 너의 중학교 졸업식이었지.
You received an award in front of the entire school.
상을 받으셨어요 학교 전체 앞.
I was on cloud nine.
나는 클라우드 9에있었습니다.
And this was your high-school graduation.
그리고 이게 너의 고등학교 졸업식이었지.
And this was taken at the institute after you passed the bar exam.
그리고 이건 연구소에서 찍은건데 변호사 시험에 합격한 후.
After the ceremony, we ate at the cafeteria there.
행사가 끝난 후 우리는 거기 식당에서 먹었어.
We had seasoned deodeok, bulgogi, and winter-cabbage-doenjang soup.
우리는 양념 더덕, 불고기를 먹었습니다. 그리고 겨울 양배추 된장 국.
You really enjoyed them.
정말 즐거웠어요.
Ta-da.
짜잔.
Here.
여기.
Open up.
열어라.
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
You're off the IV fluids, so you need to eat.
IV 수액을 중단했으므로 식사를 해야 합니다.
Come on. Just one spoon.
어서 해봐요. 숟가락 하나만.
Here.
여기.
What...?
무엇...?
What's the matter with you?
당신에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
Kang-ho, just one spoon.
강호야, 숟가락 하나만.
Young-soon.
영순.
Hey.
여기요.
You were home.
당신은 집에 있었어요.
What brings you here?
무슨 일로 여기까지 왔나요?
You've been away for months.
당신은 몇 달 동안 집을 떠나 있었어요.
Your kimchi must've gone bad,
김치가 상했나봐요
so I brought some geotjeori.
그래서 것저리를 가져왔어요.
This is beef-bone soup.
이건 사골국입니다.
You must've been sick of eating hospital food.
병원밥을 드시느라 지치셨나봐요.
So enjoy this hot meal.
그럼 이 따뜻한 식사를 즐겨보세요.
Gosh.
이런.
You didn't have to.
그럴 필요는 없었습니다.
Is someone here?
여기 누군가 있나요?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
There are two sets of utensils.
두 가지 도구 세트가 있습니다.
- Well... - You're right.
- 잘... - 당신 말이 맞아요.
What's going on? Are you hiding someone in there?
무슨 일이야? 당신은 거기에 누군가를 숨겨?
No.
아니요.
This smells fishy.
생선 냄새가 나네요.
Don't tell me...
말하지 마세요 ...
you seduced a young doctor.
당신은 젊은 의사를 유혹했습니다.
Of course not.
물론 그렇지 않습니다.
Wait! Hold on!
기다리다! 기다리다!
Who's there?
거기 누구 있어요?
What? It's Kang-ho.
무엇? 강호입니다.
People will say it's punishment.
사람들은 그것이 형벌이라고 말할 것이다.
Young-soon.
영순.
They'll say it would've been better...
그랬더라면 더 좋았을 거라고 하겠지만...
if he'd died instead of living like that.
그렇게 살지 않고 죽었더라면.
Who'd say such a thing?
누가 그런 말을 하겠어요?
I did.
그랬어요.
I thought that way when I saw others in similar situations.
보자마자 그런 생각이 들었어 비슷한 상황에 있는 다른 사람들.
But you know what?
하지만 그거 알아요?
I was wrong.
나는 틀렸다.
Now that I'm going through it,
이제 그 일을 겪고 나니,
I know I was wrong.
나는 내가 틀렸다는 것을 안다.
I'm just...
난 그냥...
so grateful he's still alive.
그 사람이 아직 살아 있어서 정말 고마워요.
My Kang-ho.
나의 강호.
My one-and-only child.
내 하나뿐인 아이.
I'm just...
난 그냥...
truly thankful he survived...
정말 감사하게도 살아남았네요...
the accident.
사고.
I really am.
나는 정말이다.
What? Kang-ho?
무엇? 강호?
I'm telling you.
나는 당신에게 말하고있다.
She used to always gloat...
그녀는 항상 기뻐하곤 했죠...
that her son was a prosecutor.
그녀의 아들이 검사였다는 것.
You really never know what can happen to you.
당신은 당신에게 무슨 일이 일어날 수 있는지 결코 알 수 없습니다.
You should watch what you say.
당신이 말하는 것을 조심해야합니다.
When did she ever gloat?
그녀는 언제 기뻐했습니까?
It may not have been obvious, but she did.
분명하지 않았을 수도 있지만 그녀는 그랬습니다.
I can't believe you. What's the matter with you?
나는 당신을 믿을 수 없습니다. 당신에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
Whatever.
무엇이든.
I'm just upset about it.
난 그냥 그것에 대해 화가 났어요.
Gosh.
이런.
Either stop dieting or stop eating meat.
다이어트를 중단하거나 고기를 먹지 마십시오.
Choose one!
하나를 선택하세요!
Be quiet!
조용히 하세요!
You'd better not...
그러지 않는 게 좋을 거야...
run your mouth at the mill.
공장에서 입을 놀리세요.
What? Run my mouth?
무엇? 내 입으로 뛰라고?
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
What do you take me for?
나를 무엇으로 생각합니까?
I'm not like you.
나는 당신과 다릅니다.
You have no idea how tight-lipped I am.
당신은 내가 얼마나 입을 다물고 있는지 전혀 모릅니다.
If I was born during the Japanese colonization,
내가 일제강점기에 태어났다면,
I would've been someone like Mr. Kim Gu.
나도 김구씨 같은 사람이었을 텐데.
Mr. Kim Gu once said this.
김구 선생은 이런 말을 한 적이 있다.
"In the end, everything stems from yourself."
"결국 모든 것은 자기 자신에게서 비롯된다."
So you'd better not run your...
그러니까 달리지 않는 게 좋을 거야...
I mean, you'd better not tell a soul about this.
내 말은, 이것에 대해 아무에게도 말하지 않는 것이 좋겠다는 것입니다.
Got it?
알았어요?
Anyway, this is a secret.
어쨌든 이건 비밀이에요.
So you can't tell anyone.
그러니 누구에게도 말할 수 없습니다.
♫ Kang-ho is stupid ♫
♫ 강호는 바보야 ♫
♫ It's a secret ♫
♫ 비밀이에요 ♫
♫ so you can't tell anyone ♫
♫ 아무에게도 말할 수 없도록 ♫
♫ Kang-ho is stupid ♫
♫ 강호는 바보야 ♫
What?
무엇?
I thought he just injured his leg.
나는 그가 단지 다리를 다친 줄 알았다.
Did you take your evening medication before you heard that?
저녁 시간을 보냈나요? 그 말을 듣기 전에 약을 먹었나요?
Of course.
물론.
If I misheard them,
내가 잘못 들었다면,
you can chop off my ears with a chainsaw.
전기톱으로 내 귀를 잘라낼 수도 있어요.
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
And why would I do that?
그리고 내가 왜 그런 짓을 하겠어요?
I'd just burst your eardrums.
난 그냥 당신의 고막을 터뜨릴 것입니다.
Hold on. That's not important right now.
기다리다. 지금은 그게 중요하지 않아요.
Then what will happen to Kang-ho?
그렇다면 강호는 어떻게 될까요?
Nothing more will happen to him.
그에게는 더 이상 아무 일도 일어나지 않을 것입니다.
He's already stupid.
그는 이미 바보입니다.
I'm sorry for keeping you out here by yourself.
당신을 여기 혼자 있게 해서 미안해요.
I just don't want you...
난 단지 당신을 원하지 않아요...
to see him...
그를 만나러...
in that condition.
그 상태에서.
But...
하지만...
you know me, right?
너 나 알지?
I'll never give up.
나는 결코 포기하지 않을 것이다.
Everyone had lost hope. They said he'd never wake up.
모두가 희망을 잃었습니다. 그들은 결코 깨어나지 않을 것이라고 말했습니다.
But look.
하지만 보세요.
He survived.
그는 살아 남았습니다.
And since he survived,
그리고 그는 살아남았기 때문에,
I'm going to make him live.
나는 그를 살려낼 것이다.
He'll get up, walk, and even run.
그는 일어나서 걷고 심지어 달릴 것입니다.
He's seven now.
그는 이제 일곱 살입니다.
He'll be eight next year and nine the year after.
그 아이는 내년에 여덟 살이 될 거예요 그리고 그 다음 해에는 9번.
I'll raise him all over again.
나는 그를 다시 키울 것이다.
Just watch and see.
그냥보고 참조하십시오.
Our son...
우리 아들...
will walk out of that room.
그 방에서 나갈 것이다.
He'll stand here...
그 사람은 여기 서 있을 거에요...
and look at you.
그리고 당신을보세요.
I'll make sure he does.
나는 그가 그렇게 하도록 할게요.
No matter what.
무슨 일이 있어도.
Clean and Odor-Free Korean Smart Piggery
깨끗하고 냄새가 없습니다. 한국형 스마트돼지
You're so handsome.
당신은 정말 잘 생겼어요.
Did you sleep well?
잘 잤어요?
Doesn't this look tasty?
이거 맛있어 보이지 않나요?
Here.
여기.
It's tasty.
맛있어요.
Cluck, cluck.
꼬꼬, 꼬꼬.
Knock, knock.
노크, 노크.
Lord!
주님!
I pray...
기도합니다...
- My Kang-ho... - My son started his own business.
- 우리강호.. - 아들이 사업을 시작했어요.
I pray it'll flourish.
번창하시길 기원합니다.
Can you hear me?
내 말 들려요?
- I pray to you, Lord. - Please save my son!
- 주님, 당신께 기도드립니다. - 내 아들을 살려주세요!
You're a mother too.
당신도 엄마예요.
So I'm sure you can empathize with me.
그래서 나는 당신이 나와 공감할 수 있다고 확신합니다.
Please.
부탁드립니다.
I pray...
기도합니다...
that he'll at least eat.
그는 적어도 먹을 것입니다.
Ta-da.
짜잔.
Here.
여기.
Just one bite.
딱 한입.
They made pumpkin porridge for you.
그들은 당신을 위해 호박 죽을 만들었습니다.
It's so tasty.
너무 맛있어요.
It's a fish.
물고기입니다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
You need to eat this.
이건 꼭 먹어야 해.
What's all this?
이게 다 뭐야?
There's sesame oil,
참기름이 들어있어요
ricecake, red chili powder...
떡볶이, 고춧가루...
Where's the rice?
쌀은 어디에 있나요?
Hold this for me.
이것을 잡아주세요.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
It's dead.
죽었어.
Is it?
그렇습니까?
Goodness me.
맙소사.
Darn it.
젠장.
What kind of a lunatic put an eel in a rice bowl,
무슨 미친놈이냐 밥그릇에 장어를 담고,
and put it out here?
그리고 여기에 내놓을래?
It was me.
나였어.
What?
무엇?
Your wife caught it...
아내가 잡았어요...
by the stream while taking a walk.
산책하는 동안 개울가에서.
She told me to bring it here because it was a wild eel.
여기로 가져오라고 하더군요 야생 장어였기 때문이다.
She scared me to death a few days ago when she brought home...
그녀는 나를 몇 번 겁에 질려 죽게 만들었어요 며칠 전 그녀가 집에 데려왔을 때...
a wild rattlesnake.
야생 방울뱀.
Since we're here,
우리가 여기 왔으니까,
shouldn't we go inside and check on them?
우리가 안으로 들어가서 확인해 봐야 하지 않을까?
Right, we should.
그렇죠, 그래야죠.
Gosh.
이런.
Young-soon.
영순.
Young-soon?
영순?
What are you doing there?
거기서 뭐하는거야?
Goodness. There you were.
선량. 거기 있었어요.
Come here.
이리 오세요.
We just came...
우리 방금 왔는데...
to give you this.
이것을 당신에게 주기 위해.
This tea is made with mulberry branches. He should try it.
이 차는 오디로 만들어졌습니다. 가지. 그는 그것을 시도해야 합니다.
- Mulberry branches? - Yes.
- 멀베리 가지요? - 예.
Apparently this is helpful for people who suffer from paralysis.
분명히 이것은 도움이 됩니다. 마비로 고통받는 사람들.
We all suffer from paralysis at least once in our lifetime.
우리 모두는 마비로 고통받고 있다 우리 일생에 적어도 한 번은.
Don't you agree?
동의하지 않나요?
Right. I may not catch the flu,
오른쪽. 독감에 안 걸릴 수도 있고,
but I get paralyzed every now and then.
하지만 나는 때때로 마비됩니다.
What is that?
저게 뭐에요?
I was at a bookstore in town today.
나는 오늘 시내에 있는 서점에 있었습니다.
This was recommended as a bestseller,
베스트셀러로 추천받았는데요,
so I bought one.
그래서 하나 샀어요.
You like to read.
당신은 독서를 좋아합니다.
I also got these.
나도 이것들을 얻었다.
You can watch them when you're alone and lonely.
혼자 있고 외로울 때 시청할 수 있습니다.
Make sure you watch them by yourself.
꼭 직접 시청해 보세요.
Barefoot Ki-bong
맨발의 기봉
Marathon
마라톤
Don't do this.
이러지 마세요.
If you keep doing this,
계속 이러다보면
I'll become weak.
나는 약해질 것이다.
I'll want to rely on others.
나는 다른 사람들에게 의지하고 싶습니다.
But...
하지만...
But I can't do that.
하지만 저는 그렇게 할 수 없습니다.
I need to stay strong.
나는 강해져야 한다.
So please...
그럼 제발...
There's a saying.
이런 말이 있습니다.
"A mother..."
"엄마..."
"can replace anything in this world."
"이 세상의 무엇이든 바꿀 수 있다."
"But nothing..."
"하지만 아무것도..."
"can replace a mother."
"엄마를 대신할 수 있어요."
We aren't asking you to rely on us.
우리는 당신에게 우리를 의지하라고 요구하지 않습니다.
Yes, you should stay strong.
그래요, 힘내세요.
You're a mom, after all, right?
결국 당신은 엄마잖아요, 그렇죠?
Choi Kang-ho
최강호
Yong-yong
용용
"Mom"?
"엄마"?
Well done. "Mom."
잘하셨어요. "엄마."
Walk.
걷다.
That's it.
그게 다야.
Come here.
이리 오세요.
My Kang-ho. Good boy.
나의 강호. 좋은 소년.
- Is this me? - Yes.
- 이게 나야? - 예.
Gosh, I look pretty. Thank you.
맙소사, 나 좀 예뻐 보이는데. 감사합니다.
This is you.
이것은 당신입니다.
And this is me.
이 사람이 바로 나입니다.
Korean Mathematics
한국어 수학
Well done.
잘했어요.
This is a slingshot.
이것은 새총입니다.
This is a ddakji.
딱지 입니다.
This is a top.
이것은 상단입니다.
Your dad bought this robot for you before you were born.
너희 아빠가 이 로봇을 사셨어 당신이 태어나기도 전에 당신을 위해.
You were always playing with it.
당신은 항상 그것을 가지고 놀고 있었습니다.
It was your favorite robot.
당신이 가장 좋아하는 로봇이었습니다.
Do you remember?
기억하시나요?
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
Are you sleeping again?
또 자고 있는 거야?
Kang-ho, you should eat something.
강호야, 뭐 좀 먹어라.
You haven't eaten anything for days.
당신은 며칠 동안 아무것도 먹지 않았습니다.
Kang-ho.
강호.
Kang-ho?
강호?
What's wrong with you?
왜 그래?
Kang-ho.
강호.
Kang-ho!
강호!
It's common for patients who are paralyzed from the neck down.
다음과 같은 환자에게 흔히 발생합니다. 목 아래가 마비되었습니다.
They suddenly lost the ability to move.
그들은 갑자기 움직일 수 있는 능력을 잃었습니다.
They lose the will to live because of the sense of loss.
그들은 살 의지를 잃습니다 상실감 때문이다.
Do your best to take care of him.
그를 돌보기 위해 최선을 다하십시오.
If he still doesn't improve,
그래도 나아지지 않는다면,
you should consider admitting him to a facility.
그를 시설에 입원시키는 것을 고려해야 합니다.
Can a seven-year-old...
일곱살도 가능한가요...
feel suicidal?
자살 충동을 느끼나요?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
Can a seven-year-old...
일곱살도 가능한가요...
lose the will to live because of a sense of loss?
살 의욕을 잃다 상실감 때문에?
Eat.
먹다.
Eat!
먹다!
Eat! Why won't you eat?
먹다! 왜 안 먹을 거예요?
Do you seriously want to die?
진심으로 죽고 싶나요?
You get sleepy...
졸려요...
when you're full.
당신이 꽉 찼을 때.
And if you get sleepy,
그리고 졸리면,
you won't be able to study.
당신은 공부할 수 없습니다.
What?
무엇?
You get sleepy...
졸려요...
when you're full.
당신이 꽉 찼을 때.
And if you get sleepy, you won't be able to study.
그리고 졸리면, 당신은 공부할 수 없습니다.
You get sleepy...
졸려요...
when you're full.
당신이 꽉 찼을 때.
And if you get sleepy, you won't be able to study.
그리고 졸리면, 당신은 공부할 수 없습니다.
Is that why...?
그렇기 때문에...?
Is that why you haven't been eating?
그래서 밥을 안 먹은 걸까?
You get sleepy when you're full.
배가 부르면 졸립니다.
And if you get sleepy,
그리고 졸리면,
you won't be able to study.
당신은 공부할 수 없습니다.
No.
아니요.
No, Kang-ho.
아니, 강호.
You can eat.
먹을 수 있습니다.
You can eat now.
이제 먹어도 됩니다.
Look.
바라보다.
I'm eating too, right?
나도 먹고 있는 거 맞지?
So you can eat too.
그러니까 너도 먹어도 돼.
You can sleep if you're sleepy.
졸리면 자도 됩니다.
You don't have to study.
공부할 필요는 없습니다.
So please eat.
그러니 드세요.
I...
나는...
love you so much, Kang-ho.
정말 사랑해, 강호야.
I did that because I loved you so much.
나는 당신을 너무 사랑했기 때문에 그렇게했습니다.
I wanted you to be happy.
나는 당신이 행복하기를 바랐습니다.
I didn't want you to end up like Dad and me.
나는 당신이 아빠와 나처럼 되는 것을 원하지 않았습니다.
Please forgive me.
용서해주세요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Look. I understand Chairman Song ordered you to do this.
바라보다. 이해합니다 회장님 송이가 이렇게 하라고 명령했어요.
But I'm on duty right now.
하지만 지금은 근무 중이에요.
I'm also on duty.
나도 현역이야.
Mr. Yang Gu-man.
양구만 선생님.
Of course he won't open it.
물론 그는 그것을 열지 않을 것이다.
- Open it. - Yes, sir.
- 열어보세요. - 네, 선생님.
You can't do that. That's breaking in.
당신은 그렇게 할 수 없습니다. 침입하는 거죠.
Move.
이동하세요.
Mr. Yang.
양씨.
Darn it. Open it.
젠장. 열어보세요.
Hurry. Darn it.
서두르다. 젠장.
Mr. Yang!
양 씨!
Mr. Yang.
양씨.
Darn it.
젠장.
What? He committed suicide?
무엇? 그 사람이 자살했다고요?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
He crippled Kang-ho who had his fate in his hands.
그는 강호를 불구로 만들었다. 그의 운명이 그의 손에 달려 있었다.
Then he killed the sole witness and disguised it as suicide?
그리고 그는 유일한 증인을 죽였습니다 자살로 위장해서?
Gosh, Oh Tae-soo.
맙소사, 오태수.
He must really despise joining together as a family.
그 사람은 정말 경멸하겠지 가족으로 함께 합류합니다.
Oh Tae-soo?
아태수?
Diaper
기저귀
The truck driver's family lives in Yanbian, right?
트럭 운전사의 가족 연변에 살아요, 그렇죠?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Find out when and where I should announce my presidential bid...
언제, 어디서 해야 하는지 알아보세요 내 대선 출마를 발표해...
to make it most effective.
가장 효과적으로 만들 수 있습니다.
Before you do that,
그러기 전에,
get rid of all businesses or people...
모든 기업이나 사람을 제거하십시오 ...
who are related to Woobyeok Group.
우벽그룹 관계자입니다.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Also, about Yang Gu-man...
그리고 양구만에 대해서..
"Yang Gu-man"?
'양구만'?
Who's that?
저 사람은 누구야?
The truck...
트럭은...
I'm sorry, sir.
죄송합니다.
What's the matter?
무슨 일이야?
That...
그거...
Why is that here?
그게 왜 여기에 있나요?
Why is that here?!
그게 왜 여기 있어?!
I found it in the trash can.
쓰레기통에서 찾았어요.
I washed it and put it here.
씻어서 여기에 두었어요.
It's your favorite scarf.
당신이 가장 좋아하는 스카프입니다.
Who? Who said it was my favorite?
WHO? 누가 내가 제일 좋아한다고 했어?
Who said that?
누가 그런 말을 했나요?
Goodness, ma'am!
맙소사, 부인!
What's the matter with you?
당신에게 무슨 문제가 있습니까?
Get rid of it this instant.
지금 당장 그것을 제거하십시오.
- Yes, ma'am. - Ha-young!
- 네, 부인. - 하영아!
Snap out of it!
그것에서 벗어나십시오!
Why aren't you taking proper care of your traumatized daughter?
왜 제대로 안 받아? 상처받은 딸을 돌봐주나요?
Throw away all her old belongings.
그녀의 오래된 소지품을 모두 버리십시오.
Replace everything single thing with new ones.
모든 것을 새 것으로 교체하십시오.
Understand?
이해하다?
Okay.
좋아요.
Let's go out.
나가자.
You're okay.
당신은 괜찮습니다.
You're okay, my daughter.
넌 괜찮아, 내 딸.
Nothing will happen...
아무 일도 일어나지 않을 것입니다 ...
to you...
너에게...
or me.
아니면 나.
Kang-ho, look.
강호야, 봐봐.
That man used to be paralyzed too.
그 사람도 마비된 적이 있었어요.
But he received rehabilitation and exercised.
하지만 그는 재활을 받고 운동도 했다.
And now he's healthy like that. Isn't that incredible?
그리고 이제 그는 건강해졌어요 그. 정말 놀랍지 않나요?
You can do it too.
당신도 할 수 있습니다.
Let's get treated, and exercise...
치료도 받고 운동도 하고...
until you can move your fingers again.
손가락을 다시 움직일 수 있을 때까지.
Okay?
좋아요?
Gosh, your eyes are going to be sore.
맙소사, 눈이 아프겠다.
Here.
여기.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Yes.
예.
Hello, this is Hannuri Rehabilitation Center.
안녕하세요. 한누리재활원입니다.
Did you submit an application for Mr. Choi Kang-ho?
신청서를 제출하셨나요? 최강호 선생님께?
Yes, I did.
네, 그랬어요.
But we're completely full,
하지만 우리는 완전히 꽉 찼습니다.
so I'm afraid we can't admit him right now.
그래서 지금은 그 사람을 인정할 수 없을 것 같습니다.
What would you like to do? Would you like to wait?
무엇을 하고 싶나요? 기다리시겠습니까?
How long will I have to wait?
얼마나 기다려야 합니까?
I was told...
나는 들었다...
that he should start rehab before his bones become stiff.
그 사람이 재활을 시작해야 한다고 뼈가 굳어지기 전에.
I'm afraid I can't give you an exact date.
안타깝지만 정확한 날짜를 알려드릴 수 없습니다.
We need to wait until a spot opens up.
자리가 생길 때까지 기다려야 합니다.
Then could you please give me a call when there's an opening?
그럼 나한테 줄래? 자리가 나면 전화해?
Please.
제발.
Thank you. Goodbye.
감사합니다. 안녕히 가세요.
Kang-ho, your dinner is here.
강호야, 저녁은 여기야.
I can't do it.
나는 그것을 할 수 없습니다.
Why?
왜?
Why not?
왜 안 돼?
Kang-ho, just once more.
강호야, 한 번만 더.
Okay? Let's give it one last try.
좋아요? 마지막으로 한번 시도해 보겠습니다.
- I can't do it. - You can!
- 난 할 수 없어. - 할 수 있어요!
You did it earlier.
당신은 더 일찍 그것을했습니다.
You did it.
당신이 해냈습니다.
All by yourself.
혼자서.
You can do it.
할 수 있어요.
Okay. Here's the robot.
좋아요. 여기 로봇이 있습니다.
Push it over again.
다시 밀어 넣으세요.
- I can do it. - That's right.
- 할 수 있어요. - 좋아요.
See? You're doing it!
보다? 당신은 그것을하고 있습니다!
Flex!
몸을 풀다!
Feed me!
나에게 먹이를주세요!
Your call will be charged after the beep.
신호음이 울린 후 통화료가 청구됩니다.
Why aren't you picking up?
왜 전화를 안 받나요?
Are you still unwell?
아직도 몸이 안 좋으세요?
I made abalone porridge for you.
내가 당신을 위해 전복죽을 만들었습니다.
Anyway, give me a call.
어쨌든, 나에게 전화해 보세요.
Sun-young
선영
Bar Exam Meal
사법시험 식사
- I see some light. - Really?
- 빛이 좀 보이는데요. - 정말?
- Where? - There.
- 어디? - 거기.
- Is no one here? - What's going on?
- 여기 아무도 없나요? - 무슨 일이에요?
Those brats must've run away.
그 새끼들은 도망갔나 봐요.
They took our membership money.
그들은 우리 회원금을 가져갔습니다.
I heard the owner changed.
주인이 바뀌었다고 들었습니다.
- What do we do? - Me?
- 우리는 무엇을 하나요? - 나?
There you are!
거기 있군요!
Yes. It's you.
예. 당신이에요.
You should pay us back before selling the shop.
가게를 팔기 전에 우리에게 돈을 갚아야 합니다.
This is so ridiculous!
정말 말도 안 돼요!
This isn't right. Give us our money back!
이것은 옳지 않습니다. 우리 돈을 돌려주세요!
Give me back my money.
내 돈을 돌려주세요.
- Give it back! - Please explain.
- 돌려줘! - 설명해주세요.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
나는 당신이 무슨 말을하는지 전혀 모르겠어요.
I heard you sold your nail salon.
네일샵을 팔았다고 들었어요.
- That woman says she's the new owner. - What?
- 그 여자가 자기가 새 주인이라고 하더군요. - 무엇?
I see. Did you run this place with her?
알겠어요. 당신은 그 사람과 함께 이 곳을 운영했습니까?
You were supposed to clean out the shop yesterday.
당신은하기로되어 있었다 어제 가게를 청소했다.
The interior contractors will be here soon. Open the door now.
인테리어 시공업체에서는 곧 오세요. 지금 문을 열어보세요.
Hurry up.
서둘러요.
- Please wait a minute. - Wait for what?
- 잠시만 기다려주세요. - 뭘 기다려?
This can't be. No.
이럴 수는 없습니다. 아니요.
- Where are you going?
- 어디 가세요?
- I need to make a call. - Don't go far.
- 전화 좀 해봐야겠어요. - 멀리 가지 마세요.
- Okay. - We're watching you.
- 좋아요. - 우리는 당신을 지켜보고 있습니다.
The number you have called does not exist.
전화하신 전화번호는 존재하지 않습니다.
Please check and call...
확인하시고 전화주세요...
No way.
절대 안돼.
Total Earnings: $2370
총 수입: $2370
Sun-young, I think we'll become rich.
선영아, 우리 부자 될 것 같아.
Should we have some soju to celebrate this?
기념으로 소주 한잔 할까요?
You drink when it's raining.
비오면 술을 마십니다.
You drink when you feel lonely.
외로울 때 술을 마신다.
You'll soon become an alcoholic and get the shakes.
당신은 곧 다음 사람이 될 것입니다. 알코올 중독자이고 쉐이크를 받으세요.
Then you won't be able to work.
그러면 일을 할 수 없습니다.
- Come on. Don't be like that. - But...
- 어서 해봐요. 그렇게 하지 마십시오. - 하지만...
Fine.
좋아요.
I'll let you go today.
오늘은 널 보내줄게
- Really? - Really.
- 정말? - 정말.
- Mi-joo. - Yes?
- 미주. - 예?
Then can I go home now?
그럼 이제 집에 가도 될까요?
You'd better go straight home.
집으로 곧장 가는 게 낫겠어요.
All right.
괜찮은.
I'll send you this money later.
이 돈은 나중에 보내드릴게요.
Bye.
안녕.
Hey, little one.
안녕, 꼬마야.
Goodness.
선량.
What was the incident that just occurred?
방금 일어난 사건은 무엇이었나요?
It must've been very hungry...
많이 배가 고팠나 봐요...
to jump over that.
그걸 뛰어넘으려고.
This is what I think.
이것이 내 생각이다.
The piglet was extremely famished.
새끼 돼지는 극도로 배가 고팠습니다.
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
It must've been very hungry. Goodness.
배가 많이 고팠나 봐요. 선량.
All right.
괜찮은.
Here you go.
여기요.
- Kang-ho, aren't you hungry? - Yes.
- 강호야, 배고프지 않니? - 예.
Let's eat.
먹자.
Mom?
엄마?
- This is good. - Mom.
- 좋은데요. - 엄마.
Mom, I...
엄마, 나...
Mom.
엄마.
Why didn't you eat?
왜 안 먹었어?
You must not be hungry.
배가 고프지 않아야 합니다.
No, Mom.
아니, 엄마.
Mom, I'm hungry.
엄마, 나 배고파요.
I'm hungry!
배고파요!
Mom, I'm hungry!
엄마, 나 배고파요!
Mom!
엄마!
Goodness.
선량.
Mom, I want to eat!
엄마, 나 먹고 싶어요!
Mom!
엄마!
I'm sorry, Kang-ho.
미안해 강호야.
Just once more.
한 번만 더.
Let me become a bad mom just once more.
한 번만 더 나쁜 엄마가 되어 보자.
No.
아니요.
Mom, I can do it.
엄마, 저는 할 수 있어요.
- What a shame. - Mom, I moved my hand.
- 정말 안타깝네요. - 엄마, 제가 손을 움직였어요.
Mom, my hand... Mom.
엄마, 내 손이... 엄마.
I moved it.
나는 그것을 옮겼다.
Mom, I moved it.
엄마, 제가 옮겼어요.
I almost did it.
거의 다 했어요.
Mom...
엄마...
Sesame seeds...
참깨...
7 Best Medicines for Paralysis
7가지 최고의 마비 치료제
Mom.
엄마.
Let me do it once more. I almost did it.
한 번 더 해보겠습니다. 거의 다 했어요.
Mom!
엄마!
Like this.
이와 같이.
- Like this. - Like...
- 이와 같이. - 마치...
Mom!
엄마!
- Again.
- 다시.
One...
하나...
I'm a genius.
나는 천재입니다.
Come here.
이리 오세요.
Mom, wait.
엄마, 잠깐만요.
Mom!
엄마!
You're so mean!
당신은 정말 못됐어요!
You're eating so well.
정말 잘 먹고 계시네요.
Your mom must be so happy to see you eating so well.
엄마가 정말 기뻐하실 거에요 네가 너무 잘 먹는 걸 보니.
Yes?
예?
This is Hannuri Rehabilitation Center.
한누리재활센터입니다.
A spot has opened up so your son can be admitted next week.
자리가 열렸으니 아들은 다음 주에 입학할 수 있습니다.
Really?
정말요?
Does that mean he can receive rehabilitation starting next week?
그 사람이 받을 수 있다는 뜻인가요? 다음주부터 재활 시작?
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Thank you so much. Goodbye.
매우 감사합니다. 안녕히 가세요.
Kang-ho.
강호.
Kang-ho, you can finally...
강호야, 드디어...
You did it.
당신이 해냈습니다.
The Good Bad Mother
좋은 나쁜 엄마
I'm not an idiot.
나는 바보가 아니다.
- Butterfly. - Wrong.
- 나비. - 틀렸어요.
I just returned to my childhood.
저는 어린시절로 돌아왔습니다.
This is a chance given from above.
위에서 주신 기회입니다.
She didn't say I couldn't go out.
그녀는 내가 나갈 수 없다고 말하지 않았습니다.
Right?
그렇죠?
Kang-ho!
강호!
Choi Kang-ho!
최강호!
What did my son do so wrong for you to do this here?
내 아들은 무엇을 했나요? 여기서 이러는 게 잘못인가요?
Because his hands are now also dirty.
이제 손도 더러워졌거든요.
I can't believe you've never called.
당신이 전화한 적이 없다는 게 믿기지 않네요.
Where have you been, you jerk?
어디 있었어, 이 멍청아?
I'll earn a lot of money and pay off all your debt.
돈 많이 벌게요 그리고 빚을 모두 갚으세요.
Ye-jin! Seo-jin!
예진님! 서진!